(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Doctor Who 1963
神秘博士(老版)
The Invasion
赛博人的入侵
(Whopix fan edit)
(粉丝剪辑版 http://wp.me/p1mHFo-lH )
(第二部分. 剪辑自原视频第六季第三集第5-8小集)
(Based on English subtitles from opensubtitles.org)
(时间轴/中文翻译: 巴蛮子sz)
(ELECTRONIC SIGNAL PULSATING)
- The Cybermen.  - Shh.
- 是赛博人  - 嘘
- (WHISPERING) Where do they come from?
- I don't know, Jamie,
- 他们从哪里来的?   - 我不知道, Jamie
but they're here, aren't they?
但现在他们在这里了, 对吧?
Come on, let's go back to the canoe.
快来, 我们回到小船去
What did you find out?
你发现了什么?
- Some old friends of ours are here, Zoe.
- Who?
- 我们的一些老朋友在这里, Zoe  - 谁?
- The Cybermen.
- Yes, I'm afraid it's true, Zoe.
- 赛博人  - 是的, 恐怕这是真的, Zoe
- That's what you suspected, wasn't it?
- What on Earth are Cybermen?
- 你在怀疑的就是这个, 对吧?   - 赛博人到底是什么?
They're from another world. Inhuman killers.
他们来自另外一个世界, 没有人性的杀手
You...You're serious?
你...你没开玩笑?
We've met Cybermen before and seen what they can do.
我们以前遭遇过赛博人, 见过他们的所作所为
Where exactly are they and how many?
他们具体是在哪儿? 有多少?
- JAMIE: At Vaughn's headquarters in London...
- Hundreds of them, probably thousands.
- 在 Vaughn 的伦敦总部  - 有数百个, 可能上千
ZOE: So Vaughn's helping them.
看来 Vaughn 在帮他们
So that's what those UFOs were.
But there've been hundreds of those sightings.
看来那些 UFO 出自那个地方, 但目击报告有几百起
Aye, they must have quite an army by now.
是, 他们目前肯定有很大一支队伍了
- The thing is, where are they hiding them all?
- I don't know, Jamie.
- 问题是, 他们被藏在哪里?   - 我不知道, Jamie
- Captain, where's the Brigadier?
- At the Ministry of Defence.
- 队长, 准将在哪里?   - 在国防部
I'll get on to him immediately
and tell him what you discovered.
我立刻跟他联系, 告诉他你们发现的情况
No, no, Captain.
不, 不, 队长
The people who went into Vaughn's Headquarters
那些进入过 Vaughn 总部的人
- were different when they came out, weren't they?
- Yes.
- 他们出来时有些不一样了, 对吧?   - 是的
- Do you think they're been controlled, Doctor?
- Controlled?
- 你觉得他们被控制了, 博士?   - 被控制了?
Yes, the Cybermen have means of controlling people's minds.
是的, 赛博人有控制人思想的手段
They appear to be almost normal,
but they're not, they're controlled.
他们看起来基本正常, 但其实不是, 他们被控制了
- Who is the Brigadier immediately answerable to?
- Major-General Rutlidge.
- 准将直接对谁汇报?   - 少将 Rutlidge
No cause for alarm?
Billy, do you realise what's happened?
没必要惊慌? Billy, 你明白是发生了什么事吗?
They tried to shoot down one of my helicopters.
他们试图击落我一架直升机
You were trespassing over their top-security area.
你们闯入了他们的最高机密区域
Oh, for heaven's sake.
噢, 老天爷啊
If you can't trust a UNIT force, who can you trust?
如果你连 UNIT 都信不过, 你能信谁?
There's nothing we...
没有什么我们...
- What's the matter?
- Oh. Nothing. Nothing at all.
- 怎么了?   - 噢, 没事, 完全没事
Look, Billy, Vaughn's a powerful chap, I know that.
你看, Billy, Vaughn 是个有能量的家伙, 这我知道
But surely we can at least
request a thorough investigation.
但我们至少应该可以申请进行全面调查啊
This isn't our province.
这不在我们职权范围内
- Well, then whose province is it?
- It's no good getting angry about this.
- 那, 在谁职权范围内?   - 为这事生气并不值得
You must see this from my point of view.
你必须从我的角度来考虑这个问题
All you've given me are vague reports,
你所能给我的都是模糊的报告
- nothing conclusive, no proof.
- No proof!
- 没有确切的东西, 没有证据  - 没有证据!
I'm sure this is all a misunderstanding.
I'll talk to the C in C of internal security myself.
我肯定这都是误会. 我会亲自同总司令沟通内部安全的问题
But, Billy, talk isn't going to help.
但是, Bily, 沟通并没有什么帮助
I want some sort of action, and I want it now.
我想要的是某种行动, 并且现在就要
At least get the civil authorities to investigate.
至少要拿到启动调查的授权
You'll have to leave this matter with me.
你就只能把这个问题交给我了
Will I?
是么?
If you're thinking of going to the C in C yourself,
如果你想自己去找总司令
I shouldn't bother, you'll be wasting your time.
我不会干涉, 你只是在浪费自己的时间
So you're going to do nothing?
这么说你打算什么都不做?
- What sort of hold has Vaughn got on you?
- Vaughn? I...
- Vaughn 拿到了你什么把柄?   - Vaughn? 我...
Brigadier, your UNIT force will take no precipitous
action without top-priority permission.
准将, 你的 UNIT 小组没有拿到最高授权之前, 不得擅自行动
- That is an order.  - I see, sir.
- 这是命令  - 我明白了, 长官
Well, you can override my authority
but not that of UNIT Central Command.
不过, 你可以压制我的权力, 但压制不了 UNIT 指挥中心
I'm sending a full report to them in Geneva.
我要向日内瓦递交一份完整的报告
(MACHINE BEEPING)
Have Gregory work with Professor Watkins on the machine.
让 Gregory 去配合 Watkins 教授做那台机器
Yes, Mr Vaughn.
好的, Vaughn 先生
No, wait.
不, 等等
(INTERCOM BUZZING)
- VAUGHN: What is it, Rutlidge?
- The UNIT group.
- 什么事, Rutlidge?  - 是 UNIT 的小组
- Well?
- There'll be trouble. I can't stop it.
- 怎么了?   - 会有麻烦了, 我阻止不了
- Why not? You have authority to.
- I have no authority outside this country.
- 为什么不行? 你有这个权力  - 出了这个国家我就没权管了
A report is being made to UNIT Central Control.
他们已经向 UNIT 指挥中心递交了报告
They're bound to investigate and take action.
他们肯定要展开调查、展开行动了
DOCTOR: You see, a network of tunnels underneath London.
你看, 一张伦敦地下的隧道网络
BRIGADIER: And that's where you think they might be?
你觉得他们可能在那里面?
Yes.
是的
And look. There's a main flood-relief sewer
running right underneath the warehouse.
看, 这里有一个主要的泄洪渠, 正好在仓库的下面
Yes, but if there's water in the sewers,
wouldn't that affect them?
是的, 但如果下水道里面有水的话, 他们不会受到影响吗?
Oh, no, no. Besides, many of these tunnels are dry
噢, 不, 不会. 而且, 很多隧道都是干的
and only flood during heavy rainfall.
只有在暴雨的时候才会积水
What do we do? Pray for a cloudburst?
那我们怎么弄? 等着倾盆大雨的到来?
Miss Watkins, this could be very serious.
Watkins 小姐, 这是非常严肃的事情
I'm sorry, but, well,
it's a pretty fantastic story to swallow.
对不起, 不过, 这事太离奇了, 难以让人接受
Yes, but so was the attack from the Yeti,
but nevertheless it happened.
是的, 雪怪袭击的事情也是这样, 不管怎么都真实发生了
With all due respect, sir, she's right.
No one believed in the Yetis until they saw them.
恕我冒昧, 长官, 她说得对. 在看见雪怪之前是没有人相信的
If you go to Central Command with this story,
they'll think you're mad.
如果你到指挥中心去讲这个故事, 他们会认为你疯了
Yes. Yes, Jimmy, you're right.
是的, 是的, Jimmy, 你说得对
'Course, what we really need is
some sort of evidence, some proof.
当然, 我们真正需要的是某种表现, 某种证据
It might be better at the moment
to find out what form this attack's going to take.
现在这个时候, 搞明白攻击可能会是什么形式, 可能更有用
- Jamie...  - What?
- Jamie...  - 什么?
That transistor radio that Vaughn gave you.
Have you still got it?
Vaughn 给你那个晶体管收音机, 还在你那里吗?
Aye, here.
是, 这里
- Brigadier, have you any IE equipment here?
- Um, Jimmy, have we?
- 准将, 你这里有IE公司的设备不?   - Jimmy, 我们有吗?
Yes, we have, sir. A computer
and various radio and radar components.
有, 我们有, 长官. 有电脑, 还有各种无线电和雷达器件
- May I see them, please?
- Certainly. Jimmy, would you...
- 我可以看看吗, 劳烦?   - 当然, Jimmy, 你去...
- I'll show you, Doctor, it's this way.
- DOCTOR: Thank you.
- 我带你去, 博士, 在这边  - 谢谢你
- Ah, there you are, Packer. Everything going well?
- Yes, Mr Vaughn.
- 啊, 你到啦, Packer. 一切都还好吧?   - 是的, Vaughn 先生
Good. Time for our little experiment.
很好, 是时候看看我们的小实验了
Mr Vaughn, I don't think you should...
Vaughn 先生, 我觉得你不应该...
- We must try the machine, Gregory.
- But it's dangerous.
- 我们必须试试这台机器, Gregory  - 但这很危险
It would be even more dangerous
if we didn't try it.
如果我们不试一下的话, 就会更加危险
We must be sure we have an effective weapon
against the Cybermen.
我们必须得确保我们有一个有效的武器来对付赛博人
- You're going to try it on one of them?
- Why not?
- 你打算在他们身上做试验?   - 为什么不呢?
Revive it. Uh, just enough
to bring it out of its cocoon.
弄醒它.  啊, 把它从茧里面弄出来就可以了
MAN: Yes, sir.
好的, 先生
(MACHINE BEEPING)
Hold it there.
稳住
Now, Gregory, connect the Professor's machine.
现在, Gregory, 连上教授的机器
- Mr Vaughn, please...  - Connect it!
- Vaughn 先生, 求你...  - 连上!
- What emotion shall I induce?
- Fear!
- 我应该设定什么情绪?   - 害怕!
Let's see how the Cybermen will react to fear.
我们来看看赛博人对于害怕是如何应对的
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
Increase the power.
加大功率
(DISTORTED HUMMING)
VAUGHN: More power!
GREGORY: That's all there is!
- 再开大!  - 已经是最大了!
(GUN FIRING)
VAUGHN: Quick!
快!
I told you, the machine isn't ready yet.
我告诉过你, 这台机器还没有准备好
- It's following the others into the sewers.
- Let it go.
- 它跟着它的同伴进入了下水道  - 让它去吧
It's gone mad. It could've killed us all.
它发疯了, 差点把我们都杀死了
Possibly, but I think we proved
that the Professor's machine can be effective.
有可能, 但我想我们证明了教授的机器是有效的
Get him to work on it, Gregory.
让他继续工作, Gregory
I want twice as much power
and I want directional control.
我要两倍功率, 还要有方向控制
Yeah, but what about that one?
好, 但那个怎么处理?
- You can't let it roam down there alone!
- Why not?
- 你不能让它在下面乱跑!   - 为什么不能?
- Well, it'll kill anything that gets in its way.
- Good.
- 它会杀死任何挡路的东西  - 很好
Anyone fool enough to be down
those sewers deserves to die.
任何想进入那些下水道的傻瓜, 都该死
This is rather like looking for
the proverbial needle in the proverbial...
这就跟俗话说的一样, 简直就是大海捞针...
- Just a minute...  - Found something?
- 等一下... - 发现什么了吗?
I don't know. Wait a minute.
我不知道, 等一下
Yes. Yes, I'm almost sure
that this is the same sort of circuit
是的, 是的, 我几乎可以确认, 这个电路基本是同一类型
that was in Jamie's radio.
跟 Jamie 的收音机里面那个一样
- But what does it do? - I've no idea.
- 但它有什么用?   - 我不知道
But it's certainly not part of that equipment.
Have a look.
但它显然不是这个设备的一部分, 你看一眼
But why put in a circuit if it doesn't do anything?
但是为什么要放一块什么也不干的电路?
Oh, it does something, all right.
The question is, what?
噢, 它是有某种用途的, 好吧. 问题是, 什么用途?
COMMUNICATOR: One hour before invasion,
入侵开始前一小时
the Cyber-transmitter units will be
launched into orbit around Earth.
赛博讯号发送装置将会发射到地球轨道上
The effect will be immediate?
会立刻生效吗?
Yes, transmissions will penetrate all areas.
是的, 会发送到所有区域
And if it doesn't work?
但如果它不起作用呢?
Humans cannot resist Cyber-control.
人类抵抗不了赛博控制
Our forces will penetrate all areas
我们的队伍将突破所有区域
and select suitable humans
for cybernetic conversion.
然后选择合适的人类进行赛博转化
- Found anything?  - No. I'm afraid not.
- 找到什么了吗?   - 没, 恐怕还没找到
What I really need is laboratory facilities.
我真正需要的是实验室设备
I'm sure that this micromonolithic circuit
我确定这个微型单晶片电路
is something to do with the Cybermen's invasion plan.
与赛博人的入侵计划有某种关系
Perhaps we can find a lab for you to work in.
也许我们能找到一个实验室让你继续研究
Oh, no, that's no problem. I can go up to London
噢, 不, 这不是问题. 我可以到伦敦去
and use Professor Watkins's laboratory
at Travers's house.
直接用 Travers 房子里 Watkins 教授的实验室
VAUGHN: Ah, come in, gentlemen.
啊, 进来, 先生们
- Well, Gregory, success?
- I don't know yet, sir.
- 怎样, Gregory, 成功了?  - 我还不知道, 先生
We've added narrow bandwidth transducers.
Should make transmission more directional.
我们给加了窄幅变换器, 应该能让发送时更有方向性
Good, good. Show me.
好, 很好, 展示一下
This is madness.
这太疯狂了
- That machine is a deadly weapon now.
- Really?
- 这个机器现在成了一个致命武器了  - 真的?
The modifications were quite unnecessary.
It worked perfectly well as it was.
这些变动完全不必要, 它之前工作得非常好
For your purposes, perhaps, Professor.
对你而言, 也许吧, 教授
I have a somewhat different use for it.
我拿它有稍微不一样的用途
All right, all right.
好吧, 好吧
Do with it what you will.
The machine's yours now.
你爱怎样就怎样吧, 这台机器现在是你的了
Now, will you let me get out of this place?
现在, 你能允许我离开这个地方了吗?
And let Isobel go free, as you promised?
并且放 Isobel 走? 你承诺过的
- But, my dear fellow, she is free.
- Free?
- 但是, 我亲爱的伙计, 她已经走了  - 已经走了?
Where? Where is she?
哪儿? 她在哪儿?
Probably sitting quite comfortably at home.
很可能正舒服地坐在家里呢
Now, then...how does one operate this?
现在, 说说...怎么操作这个?
- Careful, Mr Vaughn. Don't point it at anyone.
- No?
- 小心, Vaughn 先生, 不要对着任何人?   - 不要?
Dangerous, is it? Fear, Watkins.
很危险, 是吗? 害怕, Watkins
- Do you know what fear is?
- (STAMMERING) No, don't!
- 你知道害怕是什么吗?   - 不, 不要!
(MACHINE PULSATING)
Mr Vaughn, you'll kill him! Stop!
Vaughn 先生, 你会杀死他的! 停下!
Perhaps we should try
the effects of the machine on you, Gregory!
也许我们应该在你身上试试这台机器的效果, Gregory!
- At full power!  - No, no. Mr Vaughn.
- 最大功率!   - 不, 不, Vaughn 先生
I was only afraid
that if we still needed the Professor...
我只是担心我们可能还需要教授...
I'm aware of that.
我很明白这一点
Unfortunately, I suppose that I still need you.
Otherwise, I...
很不幸, 我觉得我还需要你. 否则, 我...
Pick him up.
拉他起来
Professor, you'll be taken back
to the factory compound.
教授, 你会被带回到工业园去
I want these machines
on the production lines immediately.
我要这些机器上生产线, 立刻
- Do you understand?  - Vaughn,
- 明白了吗?   - Vaughn
obviously I can't choose but work for you.
显然我没得选择, 只能为你工作
If I refuse, you'll torture me, you'll kill me.
如果我拒绝, 你会折磨我, 你会杀死我
I know I can't stand up to torture,
我知道我无法忍受折磨
and I don't want to die.
You're an evil man, Vaughn.
而且我不想死. 你是一个邪恶的人, Vaughn
You're sadistic. You're a megalomaniac.
你残忍, 而且自大
You're insane.
你是个疯子
I pity you, but if I get half a chance,
我可怜你, 但如果我找到一点点机会
I'll kill you!
我会杀了你!
Kill me? Would you?
杀了我?  你会吗?
Give me your gun, Packer.
把你的枪给我, Packer
Take it!
拿着!
There you are. Take it.
来啊, 拿着
Now you're free to shoot me, Professor.
现在你可以朝我开枪了, 教授
Shoot.
开枪
Shoot!
开枪!
Come on, the gun's loaded,
快啊, 子弹已经上膛了
or haven't you got the courage to pull the trigger?
难道你没有勇气扣动一下扳机吗?
Take him away.
Get work started on the machine immediately.
把他带走. 立即把机器方面的工作开展起来
UNIT Control to CO.
UNIT Control to CO. Over.
UNIT 控制中心呼叫指挥官, UNIT 控制中心呼叫指挥官, 完毕
Captain Turner here, Sergeant. Stand by.
我是 Turner 队长, 中士. 原地待命
- Isobel, will you get the Brigadier for me?
- Oh, sure.
- Isobel, 你能帮我叫一下准将吗?  - 噢, 没问题
Brigadier's on his way now, Sergeant.
What's the flap? Over.
准将在路上了, 中士. 什么情况? 完毕
- Report from red sector 1, sir, at 2030 hours...
- Hold on a sec.
- 红区１号在20:30发来报告, 长官, 说... - 等一秒钟
Right, the Brigadier's listening now.
好, 准将在听了
- Go ahead, Sergeant.
- Benton on routine observation reports
- 继续, 中士  - Benton 在监视中报告说
two guards and another man
leaving with the Professor.
有两个警卫和另外一个人, 与教授一起离开了.
- He is on their tail now, sir. Over.
- Hold on, Sergeant.
- 他现在跟在他们后面, 长官. 完毕  - 等等, 中士
Look, sir, we could intercept
and release the Professor.
你看, 长官, 我们可以拦截他们, 把教授解救出来
- Well, officially we...
- Oh, do! Please do.
- 但是, 正式来说...  - 噢, 要, 肯定要
Brigadier, if you could rescue him,
he might be able to help us with our problem.
准将, 如果你救出他, 他可能能帮我们解决手头的问题
All right, your shindig, Jimmy.
好吧, 你操办吧, Jimmy
Sergeant, tell Benton to stay with them.
I'm on my way now.
中士, 告诉 Benton 跟住他们. 我马上过来
- I'll contact him en route, over.
- Wilco, over.
- 我会在路上联系他, 完毕  - 照办, 完毕
There were at least 30 of them,
他们至少有30个人
all UNIT men and all armed, Mr Vaughn.
都是 UNIT 的人, 全都有武器, Vaughn 先生
We didn't stand a chance.
我们一点机会也没有
Out of nowhere.
They just came out of nowhere.
突然冒出来了, 他们突然就冒出来了
- And they just took the Professor?
- What could we do?
- 然后他们就把教授抢走了?   - 我们能做啥?
- There were at least...
- Thirty of them, you say?
- 至少有...  - 他们有３０个, 你说?
It was hopeless.
They shot the two guards,
完全没希望, 他们开枪射倒了两个警卫
- and they'd have shot me if...
- If you hadn't run away.
- 而且他们也会朝我开枪, 要是... - 要是你没有逃走
Well, yes.
呃, 是的
You realise, of course,
that without the Professor's assistance
你要知道, 当然了, 没有教授的协助
it will not be possible to get
the Cerebraton machine on the production line.
就不可能让精神干扰器上生产线
No, Mr Vaughn, I can.
不, Vaughn 先生, 我可以
Given a little time, I'm sure I can!
给我一点点时间, 我相信我可以!
But you have no time, Gregory.
但你没有时间了, Gregory
No time at all.
一点时间都没有
Kill him!
杀了他!
(CYBERMEN PULSATING)
I'm sorry. I can't tell you.
我很抱歉, 我不能告诉你
You've no idea what these
micromonolithic circuits are for?
你不知道这些微型单晶片电路是做什么的吗?
- No.  - Oh, my word.
- 不知道  - 噢, 天啊
I couldn't understand why Vaughn wanted
the modifications to the machine.
我没法弄明白为什么 Vaughn 想要对机器做那些改动
Why should he want a weapon like that
if he has the Cybermen to fight for him?
为什么他想要一个那样的武器呢, 都已经有赛博人帮他了?
I have no idea. Unless...
我不知道.  除非...
Professor!
教授!
You say that you've developed this machine
你说你研制的这个机器...
to produce excessively powerful emotional pulses.
可以制造强烈的情绪冲动
- Yes, that's true. - Well, that's it!
- 是的, 是这样  - 那, 这就对了!
Vaughn's going to use it as a weapon against the Cybermen,
Vaughn 打算把它用作对付赛博人的武器
once he has no further use for them.
-- 一旦他用不着它们了之后
- What, the Professor's machine?  - Yes.
- 什么, 教授的机器吗?   - 是的
Emotion is alien to the Cybermen's
nervous system. It'll destroy it.
情感对于赛博人的神经系统是异物, 会杀死它
The micromonolithic circuits.
那些微型单晶片电路
They're emotional circuits!
No wonder they weren't logical.
它们是情感电路!  怪不得它们在逻辑上说不通了
Now, why didn't I think of this before?
Now, let's see.
啊, 为什么我早没有想到? 来, 我们看看
- Now what's he up to? - I've no idea.
- 现在他在搞什么?   - 我不知道
The micromonolithic circuits are
artificial nervous systems.
这些微型单晶体电路是人工的神经系统
Once activated they will produce
the Cyber-hypnotic force
一旦激活, 他们可以产生网络催眠的力量
that controls human beings.
能够控制人类
But there are hundreds, thousands
of these circuits in IE equipment
但有成百上千的 IE 公司设备都有这种电路
- all over the world.
- Exactly!
- 遍布全世界  - 正是!
So everyone will come under their control.
所以所有人都会被他们控制
Yes, the Cybermen will take over everybody.
是的, 赛博人会控制每个人
Well, isn't there anything that we can do?
那, 有什么我们可以做的吗?
Yes, there is a way to block the signals,
isn't there, Zoe?
有, 有一种方法可以屏蔽这种讯号, 对不, Zoe?
The depolariser.
消偏振器
Worn at the back of the neck,
it will jam the Cyber-control waves.
只要套在脖子后面, 它就可以阻塞赛博控制波
Yes. Have you any neuristors here, Professor?
是的. 你这里有神经元器件吗, 博士?
- Well, a few, I think.
- Zoe, show the Professor what to do.
- 哦, 有一些, 我想  - Zoe, 告诉博士该怎么做
The invasion could come at any moment.
入侵可能随时发生
(ALARM SOUNDING)
(WHIRRING)
- Is all in readiness?
- Of course.
- 都准备好了吗?   - 当然
There is one hour to invasion time.
离入侵时间还有一小时
- Countdown will start from now.
- Excellent.
- 现在开始倒计时  - 太好了
We are moving into position now.
我们现在各就各位
Ready to transmit the Cyber-signal.
准备开始传送赛博讯号
(SIGNAL HUMMING)
(DOOR BUZZING)
Packer.
Packer
Yes, sir.
在,先生
- Have you discovered where the Professor is?
- Yes, Mr Vaughn.
- 你发现教授在哪里了吗?   - 是的, Vaughn 先生
Go and collect him.
去把他弄回来
I want work started on the production
of the machines immediately.
我期望机器的生产工作可以立即开始
Go and recapture Watkins.
去把 Watkins 重新抓回来
Don't let anything or anyone stop you.
不要让任何事、任何人阻止你
- Oh, thanks!  - Thank goodness you made it.
- 哦, 谢谢!   - 感谢老天你闯过来了
- Any trouble?  - Hundreds of Cybermen about, sir.
- 有问题吗?   - 周围有百多个赛博人, 长官
The sooner we get out of here, the better.
Everybody ready?
我们越早离开这里越好, 都准备好了吗?
- ALL: Yes!
- ISOBEL: Yes, we're ready, we're coming.
- 准备好了!  - 是的, 我们准备好了, 我们来了
Listen!
听!
(TYRES SCREECHING)
We'd better get out of here,
out of the back way as quickly as possible.
我们最好离开这里, 尽快离开这后面
- Right!  - Come on, move, everybody. Quickly!
- 好!   - 快点, 动起来, 所有人, 快!
Out of the back door. Hurry it up.
从后门出去, 快点动起来
Come on, Jamie. Professor, all right? Good.
快点, Jamie. 教授, 没事吧?  好
(GUN FIRING)
- Yes, Jimmy, where are you?
- TURNER: In bother, sir. We need help.
- 是的, Jimmy, 你在哪里?  - 遇到麻烦了, 长官, 我们需要帮助
- Can you give us a chopper?
- Yes.
- 你能给我们派一架直升机吗?   - 可以
- Can you make sector five?
- We can try, sir.
- 你们能赶到第五区吗?   - 我们可以试试, 长官
Right, I'll get the chopper there. Out.
好, 我让直升机去那里, 挂了
How could they escape the Cyber-control?
他们怎么能摆脱赛博控制?
It's that Doctor, something to do with him.
是那个博士, 跟他有点关系
You should've got rid of him
when you had the chance.
你有机会的时候应该干掉他的
Shut up, Packer!
闭嘴, Packer!
I must go on with the invasion.
我必须去继续推进入侵的事情
But what about the Professor?
但教授怎么处理?
Without him, we can't make any more machines.
没有他, 我们制造不了任何机器
Without machines, we can't control the Cybermen.
没有机器, 我们控制不了赛博人
Let me worry about that.
让我来操心这个事吧
For the moment, I have the Cybermen
exactly where I want them.
就目前而言, 赛博人正好在我期望它们所在的位置
Yeah, but for how long?
是, 但会持续多久?
Now, can you honestly say
that everything's going according to plan?
现在, 你能否实话告诉我, 是不是所有事情都会按计划走?
That nothing's been overlooked?
Well, can you?
没有漏掉什么吧? 怎样, 能吗?
Just obey my orders!
服从我的命令就是!
Now, get in touch with the compound
and have the radio beam projected.
现在, 联系工业园, 将无线电信号发送出去
The invasion fleet must be brought in.
必须得把入侵的舰队带进来
Now, Doctor, we must deal with
this invasion you say is coming.
现在, 博士, 你所说的即将来临的这场入侵, 我们必须对付它
Yes, at least we know where they'll land.
是的, 至少我们知道他们会在那里着陆
They'll home in on Vaughn's radio signal.
它们会沿着 Vaughn 的无线电讯号过来
Would we be able to pick them off
with anti-missile missiles?
我们能够用反导导弹拦截它们吗?
Yes, that's a good idea.
We might have a try.
嗯, 这是一个好主意. 我们可以试一试
Right. There's a base near Henlow Downs.
Er, just a minute.
好, 在 Henlow Downs 附近有一个基地. 呃, 等一下
- Sergeant Walters?
- Oh, Zoe, sit down, dear. It's a bit bumpy.
- Walters 中士吗?   - 噢, Zoe, 坐下, 有一点颠簸
- Now, how's Jamie's leg?
- Oh, it's just a slight flesh wound.
- 现在 Jamie 的脚怎样了?   - 哦, 只是有点轻微的皮外伤
But he's furious, because the Army doctor
won't let him walk on it.
但他吵得厉害, 因为军队医生不让他走路
Well, he would be, wouldn't he?
How's the Professor?
啊, 他会的, 对吧? 教授怎样?
Oh, he'll be all right.
Isobel's with him.
噢, 他会没事的. Isobel 在陪着他
(DOCTOR SIGHS)
- Anything I can do, Doctor?
- Well, I...
- 我能做点什么吗, 博士?   - 唔, 我...
I suggest that you...
you go with the Brigadier.
我建议你...你跟准将走
As much as I detest computers, I...
鉴于我如此讨厌电脑, 我...
I think that remarkable brain of yours
will come in very handy.
我觉得你那聪明的脑袋瓜会更有用
Right. What are you going to do?
好. 你打算做什么?
I think it's about time I had
a serious talk with our Mr Vaughn.
我觉得是时候去跟我们的 Vaughn 先生进行一次严肃的谈话了
What, go back?
But he'd kill you as soon as look at you.
什么, 又回去? 但他会一看见你就杀了你的
No, we need time
if we're going to stop this attack,
不, 我们需要时间, 如果我们想要阻止这场攻击的话
and I think I can get us that time.
而我觉得我可以帮我们争取到那些时间
No, this is madness.
I can't afford to let you take that risk.
不, 这太疯狂了. 让你去冒险, 我承担不起这责
You can't afford not to, Brigadier.
不让我去的话, 你也承担不起, 准将
If you're going to attack
the Cybermen with missiles,
如果你打算用导弹攻击这些赛博人
they're going to retaliate,
and we want to know how and with what.
他们就会反击, 我们需要知道用什么方式、什么武器
- But how can you find that out?
- I'll leave my radio on
- 但你怎么能搞到那些信息?   - 我会把无线电开着
and then you'll hear every word
that passes between me and Vaughn.
你们就能听到我和 Vaughn 之间的每一个字
But you'll never get near the place.
The whole area will be crawling with Cybermen.
但你不能靠近那个地方, 那里将会挤满了赛博人
Oh, there's one place
where there'll be no Cybermen.
哦, 有一个地方不会有赛博人
- Where's that?  - In the sewers.
- 哪里?   - 下水道里
UNIT Control. This is the Doctor.
UNIT 控制中心, 我是博士
- Is Brigadier there, please?
- WALTERS: Hold on a moment, sir, I'll get him.
- 准将在吗, 请问?   - 等一下, 先生, 我去叫他
(STATIC BUZZING)
BRIGADIER: Yes, Doctor, go ahead.
好了, 博士, 请说
Er, Brigadier, I've just entered the sewers.
呃, 准将, 我刚刚进入了下水道
I'm going to make my way to Vaughn's headquarters.
正要前往 Vaughn 的总部
I'll give you a call when I get there.
等我到了那里我会呼你
Right. We'll have a chopper in the area
好, 我们会安排一架直升机守那个区域
- in case you get in trouble.
- Thank you.
- 以防你万一遇到麻烦  - 谢谢你
(WATER DRIPPING)
And all the main communication centres
are now manned by our forces?
所有的主通讯中心都已经被我们的人控制了吧?
Yes, but, um...
是的, 但是, 呃...
What? But what, Packer?
怎么了, 但是什么, Packer?
Well, we can't make a complete takeover
without a full invasion force.
只是, 没有一支完整的入侵队伍的话, 我们没法完全掌控
They'll arrive, Packer, they'll arrive.
他们会到的, Packer, 他们会到的
And when they do,
等他们到了
there won't be one city in the entire world
that we don't control.
整个世界没有一个城市我们掌控不了
Think of it, Packer, the entire world!
想想吧, Packer, 整个世界!
(ALARM SOUNDING)
It's the security alarm,
the UNIT forces must have...
是安全警报, UNIT 的队伍肯定已经...
Packer.
Packer
There you are.
你在啊
I hope I haven't called
at an inconvenient moment, but I...
我期望我来访的时间没有给你带来不便, 但是我...
I would rather like a word with you.
我想要跟你说两句话
Clever of you to avoid our Cyber-control beam.
你很聪明, 想要躲开我们的赛博控制波
Oh, it was nothing.
噢, 那没什么
I'll...I'll come up, I know the way.
我...我现在上来, 我知道路
He must be out of his mind!
他肯定是失心疯了
Far from it, Packer.
远远不是, Packer
Have the guards search the building,
just in case he's brought any friends with him.
让警卫们搜索整栋大楼, 以防他带了一些朋友过来
Tell the raiding party to stand by.
告诉突袭小组做好准备
- Yes, sir.
- DOCTOR: (WHISPERING) Ah, Brigadier. Brigadier.
- 是, 长官  - 啊, 准将, 准将
- Yes, Doctor, go ahead.
- I am just about to enter the lion's den.
- 收到, 博士, 继续  - 我就要进入虎穴了
I will leave the radio on as of now.
从现在开始我会让无线电一直开着
- Right. Good luck.  - Thank you.
- 好, 祝你好运  - 谢谢
Keep that channel open
and get the whole thing on tape.
一直开着那个频道, 把整个过程录下来
- Yes, sir.  - If he yells for help while I'm away,
- 是, 长官  - 如果他呼救, 而我又不在
- send in everything we've got to get him out.
- Right.
- 就把我们手头所有的人派进去救他出来  - 好的
VAUGHN: Ah, Doctor, what an unexpected pleasure.
啊, 博士, 真是不胜荣幸啊
Do come in.
请进来
And you trust them?
你信任它们吗?
Doctor, I've worked with the Cybermen
for five years, preparing this invasion.
博士, 我同赛博人合作了五年, 共同准备这次入侵
I know them, the way they think,
the single-mindedness of their purpose.
我了解他们, 他们的思维方式, 他们一根筋想要达到的目的
Then you must know what ruthless
and inhuman killers they are.
那你肯定知道他们都是冷血无情的杀手吧
Of course.
当然
But then, they are my allies, not my enemies.
但是呢, 他们是我的同盟, 不是我的敌人
Do you really think they'll honour
any bargain that you make with them?
你真的觉得他们会遵循你同他们谈好的交易?
Oh, I've planned this whole operation in great detail,
allowing for every possible factor.
噢, 我策划了这整个行动, 事无巨细, 考虑了各种因素
It was I who contacted them in deep space,
当初是我联系了深空中的他们
provided the means by which they travelled to Earth.
给他们提供了到达地球的手段
And masterminded the whole operation from A to Z.
从 A 到 Z 策划了这次行动的整个过程
(SCOFFS)
They have merely provided their advanced
scientific skills, their might and strength.
他们只不过是提供了它们的先进科技, 和一点力气
And what do they get out of all this?
那他们能从这里面得到什么呢?
What they want and what they're going to get
are two entirely different things.
他们想要什么和他们会得到什么, 是两件完全不同的事
Oh, you're a fool, Vaughn.
噢, 你是个傻瓜, Vaughn
When they get here, they'll take over.
一旦他们到了这里, 他们就会夺取控制权
All Cybermen here are conditioned to obey my orders.
根据条件, 所有赛博人都要服从我的命令
They are directly under my command.
他们都受我直接指挥
Oh, possibly. But what about the others,
out there in space?
噢, 有可能. 但另外那些呢, 在太空里的那些?
Are they conditioned to obey your commands?
他们也会按条件服从你的指挥?
If they're not, I'll destroy them.
如果他们不服从, 我会消灭他们
- With the Professor's machine?  - Yes.
- 就用教授的机器?   - 是的
With one machine?
就凭一台机器?
I'll have more made.
我会多制造一些的
But you'll have to have the Professor's
help to do that, won't you?
但你得需要教授的帮助才能做到, 对吧?
We've got the Professor.
教授在我们手上
They'll be under my command,
exactly like the others.
它们会听我指挥的, 跟其它的完全一样
But you can't be sure of that, can you?
但对此你并没有把握, 对吧?
(ELECTRONIC SIGNAL PULSATING)
Well, we can't get them all.
Let's take as many as we can.
好吧, 我们没法把它们全干掉, 能搞定多少就算多少
- Lift off the activation check.
- Coordinate programme running, sir.
- 开始激活检查  - 协同程序已经开始运行, 长官
- Link programme to telemeter guidance.
- PETERS: Roger.
- 将程序连接到测距导航仪  - 收到
Major, I think we stand a good chance of
getting at least 90 percent of them.
少校, 我觉得我们有很大可能可以消灭它们的９成
- How? We haven't got enough missiles.
- Oh, please, Major.
- 怎么弄? 我们没有足够的导弹  - 哦, 拜托, 少校
Just knocking out half a dozen of them
will do very little good at all.
只是干掉它们中的一两打的话, 完全没有多大收益
Let's try for them all.
我们得尽力把它们全搞定
Look, miss, I know my business and
I'm telling you we haven't got enough missiles.
听着, 小姐, 我知道我的情况, 我告诉你我们没有足够的导弹
Yes, you have.
有, 你有
These things are coming in in a formation pattern.
这些家伙是以一种编队阵型过来的
Now if you set your missiles carefully,
you can set up a chain reaction of explosions.
现在如果你们仔细设定你们的导弹, 就可以引发链式爆炸
No, there isn't time to compute
all the relevant information.
不行, 没有足够的时间来计算所有相关的因素了
- They'd be on top of us by then.
- Give me 30 seconds.
- 到时候它们已经到我们头上了  - 给我３０秒
Give her what she asks, Major. 30 seconds.
她要就给她吧, 少校, ３０ 秒
- But, sir, this is ridiculous!
- Just 30 seconds.
- 但是, 长官, 这很荒谬!   - 就３０秒
- Hold for 30 seconds!
- Sir, that doesn't give us much time.
- 暂缓３０秒!   - 长官, 给我们的时间不多了
All right, Sergeant, I know.
Countdown to begin at T minus 45 seconds.
好了, 中士, 我知道. 开始４５秒倒计时
Here. Feed this into your computer.
给, 把这个输入到你们电脑里面去
Do as she says. Now. I'll take over.
按她说的做. 现在, 我来接管
Sir.
长官
- You'd better be right.  - I am.
- 你最好是对的  - 我当然是
T minus 45 seconds from...now.
４５秒倒计时...开始
(WHIRRING)
Once the Cybermen take over,
they'll destroy the Earth as we know it!
一旦赛博人占领这里, 它们会毁灭地球的, 我们都知道!
You're just playing for time, aren't you?
你只是在拖延时间, 对吗?
I'm trying to stop you
from destroying the human race!
我是在尽力阻止你毁灭整个人类种族!
Your UNIT friends...
你那些在 UNIT 的朋友...
You presumably managed to protect them
from the Cyber-control as well?
估计你肯定设法保护了他们, 不让他们受到赛博控制波影响?
What are they planning?
他们在谋划些什么?
I don't know what you're talking about.
我不知道你在说些什么
Packer?
Yes, sir.
在, 先生
- Is the radio beam in the compound aligned yet?
- Yes, sir, it's all ready.
- 工业园的无线电波已经调校好了么?   - 是的, 先生, 都准备好了
Good. Then link the beam to the invasion fleet.
好, 那把它跟入侵舰队的讯号连接起来
Right, Mr Vaughn.
好的, Vaughn 先生
Now whatever it is
your UNIT friends are trying to do...
现在, 不管你在 UNIT 的朋友打算做什么...
it's too late.
都来不及了
COMMUNICATOR: The first transporter fleet
is being attacked and destroyed.
第一支传送舰队已经被攻击了, 全部毁灭
- You have betrayed us.  - No!
- 你背叛了我们  - 没有!
The failure of this mission is due to you.
这次任务的失败都是因为你
We will now take over the invasion.
我们现在要接管入侵行动
No! Wait! Give me time!
不, 等等! 给我点时间!
I can stop this opposition!
我可以组织那些抵抗者!
There is no more time.
不会有更多时间了
We no longer need you.
我们不再需要你了
The Cyber-Megatron bomb will be delivered.
即将发送赛博超级炸弹
We must destroy life on Earth completely.
我们必须完全摧毁地球上的生命
Every living being.
所有活着的生物
You can't do this! I won't let you!
你不能这么做! 我不允许你这样!
You cannot stop us.
你阻止不了我们
No one can.
没谁能
Now you're beginning to understand
the Cybermen, Vaughn.
现在你开始了解赛博人了, Vaughn
You can't make bargains with them!
你不可能跟它们做交易!
I won't let them take over, I won't!
我不允许他们接管, 我不!
You think you're indestructible?
Well, I can destroy all of you!
你觉得你们是无法战胜的? 好, 我要摧毁你们全部!
(ELECTRONIC SIGNAL PULSATING)
Packer! Packer! Where are you?
Packer! Packer! 你在哪儿?
Vaughn, what have you done to us?
What have you done?
Vaughn, 你对我们做了什么? 你做了什么?
(HUMMING)
(SCREAMING)
(ELECTRONIC SIGNAL PULSATING)
Vaughn!
Where is the transmitter for the radio beam?
无线电波发射器在哪里?
We can't fight them.
They're too powerful, too many of them.
我们打不过它们的. 它们太强大了, 人数太多了
Oh, don't be a fool, man.
Where do we turn it off?
噢, 别犯傻了, 伙计. 我们在哪里关掉它?
- At the compound, but they'll be there.
- Right. We must stop them.
- 在工业园, 但它们快到那里了  - 好, 我们必须阻止它们
Brigadier, Brigadier, this is the Doctor.
准将, 准将, 我是博士
Can you still hear me?
你还能听到我吗?
Yes, Doctor, we heard everything.
What do we do?
是的, 博士, 我们都听到了. 要我们做什么?
There are only two possibilities.
只有两种可能
We must either cut off the transmitter
of the radio beam at the compound
我们必须要么关掉工业园的无线电波发射器
or destroy the Cyberman spaceship.
要么摧毁赛博人的飞船
How much time do we have?
我们有多少时间?
Oh, I've no idea.
It could be minutes or hours.
哦, 我 不知道. 有可能是几分钟或者几小时
Depends how long it takes them
to prepare this bomb of theirs.
取决于它们准备那个炸弹要多久
Well, destroying the spaceship
is going to take time.
呃, 摧毁飞船需要不少时间
Then there's only one chance.
The radio beam.
那就只有一个机会了, 无线电波
Er, wait. Vaughn.
呃, 等等, Vaughn
Now, Vaughn, will you help us?
现在, Vaughn, 你会帮助我们吗?
We must try to get to the controls
of the radio beam.
我们必须尽力赶到无线电波的控制台
We'll never do it in time unless you help us!
除非有你帮助我们, 否则我们不可能及时赶到!
You still think you have a chance?
你还是觉得你有机会?
- Yes, if you'll help us!
- Help you? Why should I?
- 是的, 只要你肯帮我们!   - 帮你们? 我应该吗?
Well, to save us! To save yourself!
对, 救我们! 救你自己!
And if I survive, what future have I got?
What will the world do with me?
如果我活下来, 我有什么未来? 这个世界会把我怎么样?
Oh, for heaven's sake,
stop thinking about yourself!
噢, 老天啊, 别再只为你自己考虑了!
Think of the millions of people on Earth
who are about to die!
想想地球上亿万的人就要死了!
Appealing to my better nature.
呼唤我人性中善的一面
No.
不
If I help you, it'll be because I hate them.
如果我帮你, 也只是因为我恨它们
The Cybermen, my ''allies''.
赛博人, 我的＂同盟＂
You think I'm mad,
that all I want is power for its own sake.
你觉得我疯了, 觉得我想要的就只是权力本身
No, I have to have power.
不, 我必须得有权力
The world is weak, vulnerable,
a mess of uncoordinated and impossible ideals.
这个世界很虚弱、脆弱, 满是不协调、不现实的理念, 一团乱麻
It needs a strong man, a single mind.
它需要一个强人, 一个独立的头脑
- A leader!  - Vaughn, will you listen?
- 一个领袖!   - Vaughn, 你肯听吗?
Right.
好
I'll help you to destroy them because I hate them.
我会帮你摧毁它们, 因为我恨它们
They... destroyed my dream.
它们...摧毁了我的梦
What are you doing?
你在做什么?
We must destroy them!
我们必须摧毁它们!
We want to get to
the radio transmitter control room!
我们想要赶到无线电发射器的控制室!
The Cybermen don't know we're here yet.
Let's keep that element of surprise.
赛博人还不知道我们在这里. 我们先保留这份惊喜吧
Come on, we'll try down here.
快来, 我们试试这下面
(ELECTRONIC SIGNAL PULSATING)
- Now they know we're here.  - Right.
- 现在它们知道我们在这里了  - 对
Up there. We'll go over the roofs.
上那边. 我们从屋顶过去
VAUGHN: That's it.
就这样
(PANTING) That's where we've got to get to.
Down there.
那是我们要去的地方, 那下面
Look out!
小心!
(ELECTRONIC SIGNAL PULSATING)
(CLATTERING)
Look out!
小心!
Come on!
快点!
- Is this the only way down?  - Yes.
- 只有这一条路下去吗?   - 是的
Come on, then.
来吧, 那
Cybermen! Take cover!
赛博人! 隐蔽!
They've got a main control switch
for the radio beam.
无线电波有一个总开关
There doesn't seem to be
any Cybermen about at all. That's odd.
这周围似乎完全没有赛博人, 这很奇怪
Well, let's not waste time, then.
好, 我们别浪费时间了, 走
Look behind you!
看你后面!
(ELECTRONIC SIGNAL PULSATING)
(SCREAMING)
Whoa!
哇!
(SHOUTING)
Doctor, get down! Right, bazooka!
博士, 蹲下! 好, 火箭炮!
- You all right, Doctor?  - What?
- 你没事吧, 博士?   - 什么?
Yes, yes, it's there, in that building.
是的, 没事, 在那儿, 那栋建筑里
The radio transmitter control,
you've got to destroy it!
无线电发射器, 你得毁掉它!
Leave it to us. Forward!
交给我们吧. 前进!
Just a second.
等一下
Oh, but I...
噢, 但是我...
That's it, that's better. Sit still.
就这样, 这样好多了. 坐着别动
(GUN FIRING)
(SHOUTING)
BRIGADIER: Grenades!
手雷!
Bazooka!
火箭炮!
That was just a dozen of them.
这才只有十几个
I'd hate to have to meet a hundred.
Forward!
我很讨厌得对付一百个. 前进!
前进!
There we are, all done and ready to go.
我们到了. 全都搞定, 可以走了
(LAUGHING) Bye-bye.
拜拜
- Bye-bye! - Bye.
- 拜拜!   - 拜
A police box?
一个警亭?
I don't believe it!
我简直不敢相信!
(WHOOSHING)